Guide to the Ronald R. Spadafora Papers 1911-2018 (bulk, 1970s-2010s) MS 3134
New-York Historical Society
- Specifics (Republican Party National Convention, 2004). Policies & Procedures. World Trade Center. Reference., circa 1980s-2000s (Offsite-box 9554)
  Mostly files on high-rise building evacuation and firefighting issues, circa 2002-2004, related at least in part to response to WTC; some reference material in the files back to 1980s. Includes James Lee Witt report on Cook County Admin Building fire of 2003. File on "Evacuation Plan" with BOMA (Building Owners and Managers Association of New York) emergency action plan white paper and Powerpoint of presentation to FDNY (2004), with drafts of FDNY's plan and other reference material. McKinsey report "Increasing FDNY's Preparedness" (final and draft with related material), 2002. Files on various matters re high-rises: sound powered phones, certificates of occupancy, alarm revisions, exit signage, codes, stairway sprinkler pressure, communications technology (files date from 2002-03, with earlier documents). Thick file of material on the 2004 Republican National Convention (RNC) at Madison Square Garden, with many maps (folded/oversize) of the floor plan of MSG and of the Farley Post Office showing media locations, etc during convention, with drafts and other material of emergency plan for the Post Office.
- Specifics (social clubs)., circa 1990s (Offsite-box 9776)
  Entire box relates to the Social Club Task Force (SCTF): training manuals, reference material (including some related to the specific Happy Land incident), procedures, memos, laws, task force annual report, etc. Acronym LPPA appears here at spots too. In various overstuffed binders. Mostly 1990s
- Specifics (social clubs). Policies & Procedures. Personal. Education. World Trade Center., circa 1990s-2000s (Offsite-box 9778)
  WTC: 1 binder labeled "Hazmat" relates to related matters at 9/11 site. 3 binders/bound matter re: AFID Battalion Chief training (see also box 9779). Bureau of Fire Prevention (circa 2004), Spadafora is Assistant Chief for Fire Prevention: various files on admin bureau matters (e.g. reorganization, budget, staff meetings) and incidents in other places (Chicago high-rise fire, Binder: Rhode Island Station Club Fire After-Action report, circa 2003), Fire Alarm Inspection Unit (FAIU) memos, NOV process, some earlier folders on hotel/high rise fires. Packet re: Frying Pan Inc response to violations to Social Club Task Force SCTF (1998).
- Specifics (South Africa)., circa 2000s-2010s (Offsite-box 9846)
  Caps from Cape Town FD and others. Framed photo. Souvenir. Badge. Shirts. Two notebooks. Immunization & other travel docs. Training materials, probably for other than South Africa too (WOF: Working of Fire). Emails, text, others. (Includes artifacts)
- Specifics (South Africa). Education. Reference., circa 2000s-2010s (Offsite-box 9361)
  Binders/manuals/instructor guide on ICS (Incident Command System/Unified Command). Relates to travel to Africa (Namibia, South Africa) for training; some logistics files on that here. CD of fire & rescue international: disaster management training in eastern Cape Province, South Africa, and other related CDs. Wildland incident management print matter (Rockies, Idaho (Chimney Creek Complex), Montana (Lolo Creek). FDNY IMT badges, lanyards, etc. Print matter: Incident response and other pocket guides. (Includes digital formats, artifacts)
- Specifics (South Africa). Education. Reference., circa 2000s-2010s (Offsite-box 9425)
  Print matter: book re: "The Cape Aflame" and 2 other Africa-related books, Student manual for Basic Incident Command System, 2 re: firefighting on wildland and related leadership, emergency response guidebook (2012), field operations guides, fireline handbook. LOTS of CDs/DVDs with Powerpoints, South Africa photos, etc and FDNY training tools (Welcome to FDNY, etc.). (Includes digital formats)
- Specifics (WNYF article incidents). Education. Personal. Reference., circa 1980s-2010s (Offsite-box 9748)
  5 VHS on fire investigations. Several books/print matter on first aid, medical. File with articles etc on Spadafora's writing re: helicopter crash over Hudson. Ref material and CD of photos re: flight 587 crash. Pistol license info handbook. Spadafora's personal fire marshal notepads (1984-86ish). Spadafora's own coursework: management by objectives ref material, fire science. 1912 Lawrence strike ref material. Material re: CFR (certified first responder), including protocols, training, student guide, exercises for fitness, etc. Recruitment flyer for EMT/paramedic. (Includes digital formats)
- Specifics (WNYF article incidents). Reference., circa 2010s (Offsite-box 9039)
  Files re: Spadafora's articles for WNYF, circa 2003-14: "Man in the Mud" article, East Flatbush fire, After Action Review (AAR), Addressing the Media, 2003 Blackout, Collapsed Crane in Manhattan, Bronx fire (2013), Tornadoes/Storm (2010). Drafts, reference material, final publication, CDs and floppies with photos, etc. (Includes digital formats)
- Specifics (WNYF article incidents). Reference. Personal., circa 2000s-2010s (Offsite-box 9213)
  Folders re: Spadafora's award as part of Diamond Plate team for web-based training kiosk (and related WNYF article). WNYF articles on pressure tanks, pier fire (2010). Half of box holds WNYF issues and admin award booklet. CDs and floppies for articles. Montana maps. (Includes digital formats)
- Specifics (WNYF article incidents). World Trade Center. Policies & Procedures. Personal., circa 1990s-2010s (Offsite-box 9869)
  Box holds various unrelated things. 3 folders re: Spadafora articles in WNYF, with docs and floppies: 4/2006 re: BQE fire, 4/2006 re: NYC Water Tunnel #3, and 2/2007 re: the John Jay College educational program for FDNY (good explanation of courses, etc.). "Apparatus Accident Packet" of blank forms for reporting, plus related safety bulletin (1998). Notebook/to-do's circa 2012, and other loose note pages and notebook on unclear topic. PANY&NY "general program coordination drawing: WTC Construction: Overall Upper Transit Hall Level" (2010). Queens North/14th Division exercise plan for December 6, 2011 (part of 2011 Command Post Exercise Series). Folder labeled "Field Units Phone #s and addresses" has unit location charts, vehicle assignments, FDNY cellular, pager and Nextel directories, etc. (circa early-mid 2000s); box has related documents loose throughout. Various laminated cards (position titles, organization charts, and contact codes) re: incident management (2003). Rules & regs for rifle & shotgun permit holders (circa 2001). Draft of Structural Collapse Rescue Operations procedure (2006) and a few other random procedures. FDNY Communications Manual (1996). Buckeye Pipe Line Assignments & Instruction (ca. 2000s). Citywide Incident Management System (CIMS) protocol document, marked "Car Copy" (2005).